谁能给我澄清一下
Clarify something for me.
聚餐的精髓难道不该在于
Isn't the point of a communal meal
互相交换看法和主张吗
the exchange of ideas and opinions?
这难道不该是讨论今日大事的时刻吗
An opportunity to consider important issues of the day?
是啊
It is.
但是每当你威胁要将
You just kind of put a damper on things
边吃边说的人至于死地之后
when you said, "The next person I see talking
我们就全无兴致了
with food in their mouth will be put to death."
如果要深究谁说了什么的话  我们能纠结一整晚
Well, we could argue about who said what all night long,
但为了回到正轨上
but to set things back on course,
我要为聚餐开启个新的话题了
I will propose a new topic of conversation.
不得了了
Great.
最棒的数字是哪一个
What is the best number?
多说一句  答案是唯一的
By the way, there's only one correct answer.
五百三十一万八千零八
5,318,008?
错误
Wrong.
最棒的数字是73
The best number is 73.
你们估计会疑惑原因
You're probably wondering why.
没没  我们没有
No. Uh-uh. We're good.
73是第21个质数
73 is the 21st prime number.
而它反过来说  37是第12个质数  而它再反过来21
Its mirror, 37, is the 12th, and its mirror, 21,
则是构成73的两个数字
is the product of multiplying--
高潮来了  也就是7和3相乘的结果
hang on to your hats-- seven and three.
怎么着  怎么着  我说错没
Eh? Eh? Did I lie?
我们懂了
We get it.
73就是数字界的查克·诺里斯
73 is the Chuck Norris of numbers.
查克·诺里斯:美国著名武术家
那是对查克·诺里斯的褒奖
Chuck Norris wishes.
同时73用二进制表示的结果
In binary, 73 is a palindrome:
是1-0-0-1-0-0-1
"one-zero-zero-one-zero-zero-one"
所以它反过来念是1-0-0-1-0-0-1
which backwards is "one-zero- zero-one-zero zero one"
两者是一致的
exactly the same.
而把查克·诺里斯的名字反着念是"Sirron Kcuhc"[无意义]
All Chuck Norris backwards gets you is: "Sirron Kcuhc."
我插一句
Just for the record,
如果你把5318008输进计算器后
when you enter 5,318,008 on a calculator,
它倒过来显示拼写的单词是"咪咪"
upside-down it spells "boobies""
记得你曾疑惑过为何
Remember when you were wondering
女生们晚上不想跟我们一起吃吗
why the girls didn't want to eat with us tonight?
是啊  我现在懂了
Yeah, I get it now.
我喜欢你的心形小吊坠  伯纳黛特
I love your little heart locket, Bernadette.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
是霍华德送我的
Howard gave it to me.
这是最好玩儿的事了
It's the cutest thing.
每当我跟他妈妈共进晚餐后
Every time I have dinner with his mom,
隔天总会收到他送我的首饰
the next day I get jewelry.
你们知道人们情人节送的这种心形符号
Did you know that the iconic Valentine's heart shape
其实它的原型并不是人的心脏
is not actually based on the shape of a human heart,
而是女性弯腰时显露的臀部形状吗
but rather on the shape of the buttocks of a female bending over?
也就是说我的七年级
Oh, so I spent seventh grade
一直都用的小屁股作为点缀了是吧
dotting my I's with little asses?
酷啊
Cool.
你好啊  佩妮  最近过得如何
Hey, Penny, how's it going?
你好啊  扎克  你来这做什么呢
Hey, Zack, what are you doing here?
我爸的公司为这家店印制菜单
My dad's company prints the menus for this place.
我来送些过塑了的新版本
I'm just dropping off some new ones laminated.
这样吐在上面以后容易打扫一点
Makes 'em easier to clean if people throw up on 'em.
猜猜我怎么想到的点子
Guess how I got the idea?
好了好了  我懂的
Yeah, I got it, I got it.
扎克  这是我的朋友们  伯纳黛特和艾米
Uh, Zack, these are my friends Bernadette and Amy.
-你好啊  -你好
- Hi. - Hey.
呼~
Hoo.
很高兴再见到你
Okay, well, it was good to see you.
我也是
Yeah, you, too.
他好帅啊  你俩怎么认识的
He's really cute. How do you know him?
我们约会过几次
Oh, we went out a couple of times.
我总被时下的表达方式所迷惑
I'm often flummoxed by current slang.
约会过是不是总代表着交媾过
Does "went out" mean "had intercourse"?
-是的  -不是  不是的
- Yes. - No, no.
但这次  是的
But in this case, yes.
有意思
Interesting.
是不是过程不太满意啊
And was it not satisfactory?
不  其实还不错
No, it was great.
只是他没有在智商层面上给我压力
He just didn't really challenge me on an intellectual level.
你不能将就一下他  然后一起去听听NPR吗
Couldn't you just fool around with him and then listen to NPR?
NPR:美国公共电台
没用的  扎克连NPR的全称都拼不出来
Wouldn't help. Zack can't even spell NPR.
我跟霍华德相处就是这么做的
It's what I do with Howard.
我比他要聪明
I'm much smarter than he is.
但保护他的男子气概是很重要的
But it's important to protect his manhood.
呼~
Hoo.
你怎么了
What's the matter?
我只是突感气血涌动
I'm suddenly feeling flushed.
我的心率加速  掌心冒汗
My heart rate is elevated, my palms are clammy,
口干舌燥
my mouth is dry.
还有  我只是不由自主地想说"呼~"
In addition, I keep involuntarily saying "hoo."
我想我们明白发生了什么  是吧
Oh, we know what's causing that, don't we?
毫无疑问
It's no mystery.
我明显是患有感冒
I obviously have the flu
及其突发性妥瑞综合症
coupled with sudden-onset Tourette's syndrome.
妥瑞症:运动协调性疾患
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 翻译制作
更多美剧原创翻译 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：米小勒  小蛮腰  海因里希  Joanna
后期：老蛙    时间轴：小e
■
校对：Vin      总监：YY
生活大爆炸第四季第十集
听说生物试验室发生的事故了吗
Did you hear about the accident at the bio lab?
-没  -发生了什么事
- No. - What happened?
他们给老鼠注射了放射性同位素
They were injecting rats with radioactive isotopes
但其中的一名技术员被咬了
and one of the techs got bit.
那他得到了超能力吗
Did he get superpowers?
没  他被缝了五针外加一针破伤风针剂
No, he got five stitches and a tetanus shot.
太令人失望了
Oh. Well, that's disappointing.
为何这么说
Why?
如果你在试验室被放射性动物咬伤
Well, you get bit by a radioactive animal in a lab,
你肯定想成为超级英雄的
you kind of want to turn into a superhero.
但谁又想变成鼠魔侠呢
Yeah, but who'd want to become Rat-Man?
谁不想啊
Who wouldn't?
你可以在迷宫里横冲直撞
You could zip through a maze in nothing flat,
钻进很小的地洞
squeeze through really small holes,
而且只要蹦跶几下就能让餐馆关门
and shut down restaurants in a single bound.
而且最棒的是  如果我是鼠魔侠
And the best part is, if I were Rat-Man,
你就可以当我的跟班  鼠娃
you could be my sidekick, Mouse Boy.
鼠娃
Mouse Boy?
你不喜欢鼠娃吗
You don't like "Mouse Boy"?
那害虫娃呢
How about "Kid Vermin"?
首先  要是我们真有超能力
First of all, if we had superpowers,
我肯定不会是跟班  你才是跟班
I wouldn't be the sidekick. You'd be the sidekick.
鼠魔侠才不会是跟班呢
Rat-Man is nobody's sidekick.
莱纳德  你说句公道话
Leonard, settle this.
我们俩  谁更像跟班
Of the two of us, who's the obvious sidekick?
没错  莱纳德  你说是谁
Yeah, Leonard, who?
高中毕业十二年了  我还是悲催地混在书呆子帮里
12 years after high school, and I'm still at the nerd table.
你是不是把这个人的脑子切得太薄了点
Aren't you slicing that man's brain a little too thin?
我这要是在奎兹诺餐厅
It's too thin if I were making
做英尺人脑三明治的话  就的确是切太薄了
a foot-long brain sandwich at Quiznos.
但是放在双光子显微镜下检验的话  就不算薄
For examination under a two-photon microscope, it's fine.
好吧  你是专家
Well, you're the expert.
如果胡来才是正确的方法的话  那我闭嘴
If the correct way to do it is the wrong way, then I yield.
很好
Very well.
如果你死后将遗体捐献给科学研究的话
If you die and donate your body to science,
我保证我会把你的大脑切得跟加拿大培根一样厚
I promise to slice your brain like Canadian bacon.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果你不介意的话
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我要量一下我的体温
I have to take my temperature.
你是在监控你的生理节奏
Are you monitoring your circadian rhythms
以确定你脑部活动最旺盛的时段吗
in order to identify your periods of maximum mental acuity?
我曾经在某个暑假试过
I did that one summer.
美好的童年啊
Ah, youth.
不是  我昨晚产生了一些奇怪的症状
No, I experienced some distressing symptoms last night,
所以我每个小时都在检查自己的生命迹象
so I'm checking my vital signs every hour.
我很乐意帮你做个图表
I'd be happy to create a chart
进行一下差异分析
and participate in a differential diagnosis.
好像挺好玩的嘛
Oh, that sounds like fun.
开始吧
All right.
你有哪些症状
What were the symptoms?
心跳加速  手心出汗  口干舌燥
Elevated heart rate, moist palms, dry mouth
还有局部的血管抽动
and localized vascular throbbing.
局部是哪
Localized to what region?
耳朵和生殖器
Ears and genitalia.
有意思
Interesting.
是两个通常不会放一起说的器官
Not body parts that usually team up.
那环境因素呢
What about environmental factors?
形容一下当时的情景
Describe the scene for me.
我跟佩妮还有伯纳黛特一起在餐馆
I was sitting in a restaurant with Penny and Bernadette,
喝水  而且喝的是碳酸水  因为那是特殊场合
drinking water -- carbonated as it was a special occasion.
佩妮的朋友扎克过来打了个招呼
Penny's friend Zack stopped by and said hello
然后我就说"呼"[和"谁"同音]
and I said "hoo."
谁
Who?
扎克
Zack.
你知道是扎克还问
Then why did you ask?
-问什么  -问"谁"呀
- Ask what?  - Who.
扎克
Zack.
好吧  重头来一遍
All right, let's start over.
扎克走过来后你说了什么
What did you say when Zack walked in?
-"呼"["谁"]  -扎克
- "Hoo".  - Zack.
你为什么一直说"扎克"
Why do you keep saying "Zack"?
因为你一直问"谁"["呼"]呀
Because you keep saying "who."
我现在可没说"呼"
I'm not saying "hoo" now.
我是昨晚说的"呼"
I said "hoo" last night.
答案就是扎克  对吧
And the answer was Zack, correct?
我没问问题啊
There was no question.
我只是说了"呼"
I simply said "hoo."
好吧  我不纠结了
All right, I think I have enough to go on.
你以上症状的诱因
Possible explanations for your symptoms are,
根据可能性降序排列的结果如下
in descending order of likelihood:
甲亢  过早绝经
hyperthyroidism, premature menopause,
外星人附体  或是
hosting an alien parasite or --
以下这个结果纯粹是为了涵盖所有
and I only include it for the sake of covering
可能因素  那就是性冲动
absolutely all bases -- sexual arousal.
我在哪儿被外星人附的身啊
Where would I have picked up an alien parasite?
找到你了
There you are.
问你个问题  你最怕什么
Let me ask you a question. What are you most afraid of?
我也不知道
I don't know. Um...
核战
nuclear war.
不小心被活埋了
Accidentally being buried alive.
或者是像那种电影情节一样  突然接到一个电话
Any of those movies where you get that phone call
电话那头的人说你就要死了
that says you're going to die.
结果你还就真挂了
And then you do.
不是这些  是某个
No. Something very specific
咱俩都知道你
that we both know you,
也就是拉杰·库萨帕里  害怕的东西
Rajesh Koothrappali, are terrified of.
我家的确有二型糖尿病史
Well, type two diabetes runs in my family.
糖尿病后期会掉脚趾的
The thought of losing a toe...
是蜘蛛  你怕蜘蛛
Spiders! You're afraid of spiders!
这是什么
What the heck is this?
当然是装着一只大蜘蛛的罐子啦
A jar with a big spider in it, of course.
勇敢度测试
Bravery test.
先把手拿出来的人就是跟班
First one to take his hand out is the sidekick.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
也许吧
Perhaps.
你怕了吗
Are you scared?
没有  但这测试很白痴
No. But it's a stupid test.
是吗  要是地球危在旦夕
Oh, really? What if the Earth was in danger
而唯一拯救的方法就是
and the only way to save it was
把你的手伸进装着蜘蛛的罐子里呢
to stick your hand in a jar with a spider?
是吗  要是地球危在旦夕
Oh, yeah? What if the Earth was in danger
而唯一的拯救办法就是
and the only way to save it was to take a shower
在更衣室里洗澡  还被人看到你的裸体
in the locker room and let other guys see you naked?
得了  这事没可能发生
Oh, come on. That's never gonna happen.
快把手放进罐子里
Put your hand in the jar
不然你就一辈子做我跟班吧
or forever be revealed as my sidekick.
好吧  这就放
All right, I will.
你怎么一下子胆儿这么肥了
How did you get so brave all of a sudden?
简单
It's easy.
蜘蛛都爬到你手臂上了
The spider's crawling up your arm.
快把这货弄下来
Get it off! Get it off!
快点  拉杰
Please, Raj!
别愣着
Please.
我的血检表明甲状腺功能正常
My blood work shows thyroid function normal.
皮质醇水平也正常
Cortisol levels normal.
那你的垂体卵泡刺激素水平呢
How about your follicle-stimulating hormone levels?
谢尔顿  我还没到更年期
Sheldon, I am not going through menopause.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你这口气听着像个暴躁的欧巴桑
You said that with the testy bark of an old biddy.
我觉得我们得面对一个残酷的现实
I think we need to face the cold, hard truth:
我被佩妮的朋友扎克性唤起了
I was sexually aroused by Penny's friend Zack.
慢着  我觉得
Hang on. I don't know
我们还没考虑过外星人附体的可能性呢
that we've given the alien parasite hypothesis
这个合理假设
a fair shake.
我们还是有点逻辑吧
Let's look at this logically.
我有胃  所以会饿
I have a stomach; I get hungry.
我有生殖器  所以也可能会有性冲动
I have genitals; I have the potential for sexual arousal.
这是我们必须承受的负担
A cross we all must bear.
每次我遭遇这种艰难时刻
You know, in difficult moments like this,
我总是借助更强大的力量约束自己
I often turn to a force greater than myself.
宗教信仰吗
Religion?
《星际迷航》
Star Trek.
你看过《星舰迷航记I》吗
Did you see Star Trek: The Motion Picture?
-没有  -别看了  烂得要死  但是...
- No. Don't. - It's terrible. However...
在这部电影里我们知道
in it, we learn that
当史波克发现自己丧失了理性逻辑
when Spock finds himself drawn off the path of logic
而被他人类那部分的情绪所影响
by feelings bubbling up from his human half, he suppresses them
他就用瓦肯族科里纳心律原则压抑自己
using the Vulcan mental discipline of Kolinahr.
你的意思是  我们的人生要受
Are you suggesting we live our lives
不入流的科幻作品里的思想的影响吗
guided by the philosophies found in cheap science fiction?
不入流的科幻作品
"Cheap science fiction"?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
用科里纳规则来压抑我因为上个评论所产生的愤怒
Using Kolinar to suppress my anger at that last comment.
你现在对我这么在意
Is it possible that your concern for me at this moment
会不会就是因为嫉妒作祟
is motivated by nothing more than simple jealousy?
这我倒没想过
I hadn't considered that.
稍等片刻
Give me a moment.
好了  我想过了
All right, I've considered it.
-然后呢  -驳回这一说法
- And? - I reject it.
是因为你没感觉到嫉妒
You reject it because you don't feel jealousy,
还是因为你压抑掉了
or because you are suppressing jealousy?
我想我还是回家吃午餐吧
I think I'll eat my lunch at home.
那不是你的午餐  谢尔顿
That's not your lunch, Sheldon;
那些是尸体的大脑标本
those are the cadaver brain specimens.
就因为你切片切得不对
As they were incorrectly sliced,
害得我都把它们当成生鱼片了
you can see how I could mistake them for my sashimi.
-你好  -好啊
- Hello. - Hey.
你不是都明天洗衣服的吗
Isn't tomorrow your usual laundry night?
我常用的柔软剂超市卖光了
The supermarket was out of my regular fabric softener.
如果这一款过柔或不够柔
If this one under-or over-softens,
我得花时间处理
I'll need time to make things right.
真会未雨绸缪
That's thinking ahead.
换句话说是怎么早没想到
The alternative would be to think backwards.
这下记住了
That's just remembering.
艾米怎么样了
So how's Amy?
艾米变了
Amy's changed.
也许我该放手了
I might have to let her go.
哦不  为什么啊
Oh, no. Why?
我以为她是个高度进化的
I thought she was a highly evolved creature
纯高智商物种  就像我
of pure intellect, like me.
而最近的事件表明
But recent events indicate that
她也许不过是个屈服于低级欲望的生物
she may be a slave to her baser urges.
就像你
Like you.
这句侮辱我就当没听到吧
Just going to skip over that insult.
什么侮辱
What insult?
没错  所以我才要假装没听到
Yeah! That's why I'm going to skip over it.
你是说艾米她...
Are you saying that Amy is...
用科学的话怎么说来着...
oh, what's the scientific word...
别提科学了  她就是很饥渴
Forget science. She's horny.
好吧  哎呀
Oh! Okay. Wow.
完全是生理上的需求  我无能为力
It's simple biology. There's nothing I can do about it.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你这是什么意思
What are you suggesting?
我的意思是  也许你可以对
I'm suggesting there might be something
艾米的欲望  做点什么
you could do about... Amy's urges?
切除人的卵巢是犯法的
It's illegal to spay a human being.
好吧  我不是这意思
Yeah. That's not what I had in mind.
你是说我自己可以做什么
You mean... something I could do.
一点没错
Exactly.
好吧  我一直想避免这么做
Well, I was hoping to avoid this.
但我想还是勉为其难一下吧
But I might as well get it over with.
谢谢  佩妮
Thank you, Penny.
我会告知你结果的
I'll let you know what happens.
哎呀  艾米  你真是个幸运儿
Oh, Amy, you lucky girl.
你好  我是谢尔顿·库珀博士
Yes. This is Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
请问你是扎克·强生吗
Is this the Zack Johnson
和我邻居佩妮交媾的那个
who used to have coitus with my neighbor Penny?
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to bother you.
你好  我想找扎克·强生
Hello. I'm looking for a Zack Johnson
曾和我邻居佩妮交媾的那位
who used to have coitus with my neighbor Penny.
交媾  就是性交
Coitus. It means intercourse.
我有预感你就是我要找的那位扎克
And I have a feeling I'm speaking to the right Zack.
我是谢尔顿·库珀
This is Sheldon Cooper.
好吧  就是谢利
Fine. Shelly.
对  确实很像女孩名
Yes, that does sound like a girl's name.
不  我不觉得困扰
No, it doesn't bother me.
对  叫我"臭谢利"我确实很困扰
Yes, "Smelly Shelly" does bother me.
我告诉你我为啥打给你
Let me tell you why I'm calling.
我想知道你是否有兴趣
I'd like to know if you'd be interested
跟艾米·菲拉·福勒性交
in having sex with Amy Farrah Fowler.
艾米·菲拉·福勒
Amy Farrah Fowler.
没错  这确实是个女孩
Yes, that is a girl's name.
天哪  简直就是对牛弹琴
Good grief. It's like trying to talk to a dolphin.
坑爹呐
Really?
这样来决定谁是英雄  谁是跟班
This is going to decide who's the hero and who's the sidekick?
你有更好的主意
You got a better idea?
随便哪个主意都比这好
Every idea is better than this idea.
叮
Ding!
-等等  叮什么叮  -这是铃声
- Wait. What the hell is "ding"?  - It's a bell.
我可不觉得摔跤比赛是用铃的
I don't think this kind of wrestling has a bell.
好吧  你说怎么着
Fine. How do you want to start?
不然我们喊一二三开始
I say, uh, how about one, two, three, go?
一二三开始  那是小孩子用的
One-two-three-go? That's for babies.
好吧  不然这样...
Okay, how about, uh...
各就各位  预备  开始
on your mark, get set, go?
那是赛跑用的  你想跑吗
That's for a footrace. If you want to race,
那还得出去跑
we have to go outside.
不  外面太冷了  我没穿外套
No, it's chilly outside. Didn't bring my jacket.
搞什么名堂
Oh, for crying out loud.
哪门子超级英雄还需要外套啊
What kind of superhero needs a jacket?
那你告诉我哪门子英雄会说  "那件红色紧身衣是我的"
What kind of superhero says, "Dibs on the red tights!
"那件红色紧身衣是我的"
Dibs on the red tights!"
那这样吧  预备  摔跤
All right, how about this? Ready, wrestle.
等等  现在就开始吗  还是等真的开始时
Wait. Are we starting now? Or is that what you're going to say
-再说这句话  -现在就开始
- when we do start, or...  - We're starting now!
别冲我嚷嚷
Don't yell at me!
假设还有比这更糟糕的方法耗过周五的夜晚
Suppose there are worse ways to spend a Friday night.
完全想不到啊
None come to mind.
看看他们盖的这戳  谁允许他们
Look at this stamp. On what authority
在顾客进门时往他们手上盖印子的
are they permitted to mutilate patrons as they enter?
肯定洗得掉的
I'm sure it'll wash off.
今晚总算还有点安慰
Little comfort tonight.
我看着像地狱天使
I look like a Hell's Angel.
扎克在那
There's Zack.
你确定真的想这么做吗
Are you sure this is what you want to do?
不是我想做
It's not what I want to do;
而是不得不做
it's what I have to do.
去吧  艾米·菲拉·福勒
Go, Amy Farrah Fowler.
遵循自己内分泌系统的呼唤
Follow your endocrine system.
谢谢  谢尔顿  你真是好朋友
Thank you, Sheldon. You're a good friend.
区区小忙不足挂齿
Please don't drag this out.
这玩意肯定洗不掉
This is never going to come off.
打扰一下
Excuse me?
扎克  我是艾米·菲拉·福勒  那晚见过的
Zack, I am Amy Farrah Fowler. We met the other night.
我一直在追求着纯粹的知识
I have spent my life in pursuit of pure knowledge.
直到遇到了你  才合理理性地决定
Until I met you, my decisions were founded in logic and reason
站在你面前的  是130磅沸腾的雌性激素
And yet here I stand before you, 130 pounds of raging estrogen,
渴望着抱住你的臀大肌
longing to grab hold of your gluteus maximus
来一场莎士比亚所比喻的
and make Shakespeare's metaphorical
禽兽一样的勾当
beast with two backs.
我的臀什么
My gluteus what?
另一方面
On the other hand,
看到你这一片空白傻瓜似的表情
as I look at the blank, ape-like expression on your face,
柯里纳:《星舰迷航》中瓦肯人去除感情的过程
我又决定去培养瓦肯人"柯里纳"的习惯
I have decided to adopt the Vulcan practice of Kolinar.
-再见  扎克  -再见
- Good-bye, Zack. - Bye.
呼~~
Hoo.
这样够我支撑一会了
That should hold me for a while.
法律上我有义务提醒你
I'm legally obligated to inform you
我11岁时上过空手道课程
that I took a karate lesson when I was 11.
要是我妈安排好搭车的事
I'd be a regular ninja by now
我现在早就是一合格的忍者了
if my mom could've arranged a carpool.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
我在健身中心上过普拉提课程
Well, I've been taking Pilates class at the rec center,
我的腹肌就跟哈希巧克力块儿一样
and my abs look like sections of a Hershey bar.
是吗  没关系  反正你输定了
Oh, yeah? Won't matter, you're going down!
不  你才输定了
No, uh-uh, you're going down!
有人输的话  肯定是你
If anybody's going to go down, it's going to be you.
伙计们  都30分钟了  你们还没碰过对方
Fellas. It's been 30 minutes. Nobody's touched each other.
很高兴你决定驳回你的动物本能
I'm glad you decided to reject your animal hindbrain
回到纯粹智力的领域
and return to the realm of pure intellect.
我也是
As am I.
你这是干嘛
What are you doing?
做个实验
An experiment.
没  没什么  算了
Nope. Nothing. Never mind.
你知道你赢不了的吧
You realize you can't win.
我宁愿相信  我输不了
I prefer to think that I can't lose.
你错了
You're wrong.
那只是时间问题
It's only a matter of time
你迟早会落入鼠魔侠的捕鼠器的
before you fall into Rat-Man's rat trap.
你个可悲的笨蛋
You pathetic fool!
有捕鼠器的话  难道不会抓到鼠魔侠么
If there were a rat-catcher, wouldn't it catch Rat-Man?
我没表达好
Just because I didn't express myself well
不代表我的观点也不对
doesn't mean my underlying point was invalid!
你个喋喋不休的小丑
You bloviating buffoon!
你个自恋的脑残
You narcissistic nincompoop!
你个红鬼懦夫
You crimson coward!
莱纳德  醒醒
Oh, Leonard, wake up,
你错过了不少超级英雄的精彩名言了
you're missing some very excellent superhero quips.